netspace.net.au 2007-12-03

# Netspace Online Systems - Privacy Statement

Netspace is subject to the Privacy Act 1988 including the National Privacy Principles. It respects the privacy of personal information and treats it in accordance with this statement

**1\. Whose privacy statement is this?**

> This is the privacy statement of Netspace Online Systems Pty Ltd ACN 067 116 269. We can be contacted by telephone on (03) 9811 0000 or as indicated at http://www.netspace.net.au/internet_provider/contact.php

**2\. Who is the Netspace group?**

> The Netspace group is the group of companies that are ultimately in the same ownership as us.

**3\. What kinds of information do we hold?**

> We may collect personal information such as:
> 
>   * personal details e.g. name, age, address, phone number, other contact information;
>   * computer information e.g. type, operating system, skill level;
>   * billing, credit, payment and accounting information e.g. account usage records, billing information, payment method, credit card or bank account numbers, billing and payment history;
>   * historical information e.g. how you came to be our customer, who was your previous ISP;
>   * technical information e.g. user name, password, IP address, calling number, telephone service provider;
>   * support information e.g. history of support requests;
>   * marketing-related information, such as what products and promotions we have marketed to you, whether you have received, read or responded to promotional emails, whether you have visited links in promotional emails and whether you have participated in our promotions; 
>     * If we receive a request not to send commercial electronic messages to a certain email address, we may retain details of the address and the request indefinitely in order to comply with the request.
>   * complaint information e.g. history of issues and complaints.
> 

**4\. How do we collect and hold personal information?**

> Normally, we collect personal information:
> 
>   * directly from you;
>   * from a wholesale supplier or other entity involved in service delivery to you;
>   * from our computer equipment (e.g. service usage details);
>   * in some cases, from a credit reporting agency;
>   * from marketing bureaux who carry out promotions for us;
>   * if you became our customer as a result of a business acquisition, from the vendor.
> 

> 
> We hold personal information:
> 
>   * in paper files;
>   * in computer databases and systems
> 

> 
> that we control and supervise.

**5\. Can you access your personal information?**

> You can ask for access to personal information we hold about you. We may charge a reasonable fee for giving access. We may refuse access when authorised to do so by the National Privacy Principles.

**6\. Why do we collect personal information?**

> We collect your personal information to use it for one or more of the purposes for which we collected it – they will normally be obvious from the circumstances. Our purposes include:
> 
>   * providing goods or services to you;
>   * marketing our business to you;
>   * arranging for third parties (e.g. a wholesale supplier) to provide goods or services to you;
>   * managing our financial and commercial relationship with you;
>   * providing you with information about us and our services (or another member of the Netspace group or its services) that may be of interest;
>   * managing our business and our technical facilities and planning future development;
>   * complying with legal requirements;
>   * dealing with problems and complaints;
>   * disclosure to prospective investors in or purchasers of us or our business.
> 

**7\. Who do we disclose personal information to?**

> We may disclose personal information:
> 
>   * to our wholesale suppliers and other entities involved in service delivery to you;
>   * to our professional advisers, technical and marketing consultants;
>   * to marketing bureaux who carry out promotions for us;
>   * to another member of the Netspace group;
>   * to prospective investors in or purchasers of us or our business;
>   * to our agents and resellers;
>   * to a debt recovery or credit reporting agency in case of non-payment;
>   * to law enforcement agencies in response to a lawful request;
>   * to government authorities e.g. the Telecommunications Industry Ombudsman;
>   * to anyone to whom you complain about us or our services;
>   * as required by law.
>   * and in a case where another person has claimed a bonus from us for introducing you as a first-time customer, we may advise that person whether you are a first-time customer.
> 

**8\. What if you do not provide the information we request?**

> If you do not provide the personal information we request, it may prejudice our ability and / or willingness to provide or maintain services to you. In some cases, it may be a breach of your contract with us.

**9\. What are our policies on management of personal information?**

> We manage, and require our staff to manage, personal information in accordance with this statement and the National Privacy Principles.

**10\. How do we keep information secure?**

> We keep personal information secure by several means, including:
> 
>   * storing it in controlled access places;
>   * using good security practices and technology on our network and computers, including password security;
>   * imposing confidentiality obligations on staff.
>
